Aryan Binazir

Software Engineer

aryanbinazir.dev | abinazir@gmail.com | Raleigh-Durham, NC

Profile

I'm a Software Engineer based in Raleigh-Durham, NC, with multiple years of experience in Go, JavaScript, Ruby, React, SQL, MongoDB, Docker, and cloud platforms such as AWS, Digital Ocean, and Heroku. Recently, I designed and built Triage, an open-source Kafka consumer proxy that solves head-of-line blocking.

Experience

Co-Creator, Software Engineer (team-triage.github.io), Triage ∂

2022 - present

Triage is an open-source consumer proxy for Apache Kafka that solves head-of-line blocking caused by poison pill messages and non-uniform consumer latency.

- Designed and built Triage using Go, gRPC, and Amazon Web Services (AWS) Fargate and AWS ECS (Elastic Container Service)
- Led development of Triage core components, leveraging Go, including Go Channels & Goroutines
- Enabled multiple downstream consumer applications to connect to Triage by developing Triage thin client library in Go and a gRPC service
- Containerized Triage service with Docker, streamlining the process of deployment to an AWS ECS cluster
- Automated infrastructure deployment strategy using AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK)
- Built CLI tool, written in JavaScript and available as an npm package, to simplify configuration, deployment, and teardown of Triage in the cloud
- Implemented application logic and design components allowing for the storage of poison pill messages in a dead-letter store using AWS DynamoDB
- Collaborated with a remote team of four engineers across two time zones

Software Engineer, Open-Source Projects

2021 - 2022

- Request-Djinn an HTTP webhook inspector built using Node.js, Express.js, React.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Digital Ocean Droplet, Nginx, PM2 & Tailwind CSS
- Online Outlet a commerce application created using Node.js, Express.js, React.js
- Address Buddy a contact managing application developed with Node.js, Express.js & PostgreSQL
- BookWorm a book viewing application built using Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, JavaScript & ERB

Start-Up Experience & Real Estate Investments

2011 - 2021

- Performed investment due diligence supporting opportunities for a start-up private merchant bank connecting investors with energy and other asset opportunities in emerging markets in Africa
- Invested in, sold, and rented investment properties in the United States and South Africa

Skills

Go, JavaScript (Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Handlebars.js, Jest, NPM), Ruby (Sinatra, Gems, Puma, ERB, Bundler), TypeScript, Apache Kafka (Confluent Kafka Go Client), Databases (PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis), Cloud (AWS EC2, AWS ECR, AWS Fargate, AWS CDK, AWS S3, AWS DynamoDB, Digital Ocean Droplet, Heroku), gRPC, HTTP, Docker, Linux, HTML/CSS, Git/Github, Ngrok, Nginx, Event-Driven Architectures, Microservices

Education

Master of Business Administration (MBA),

2012

Gordon Institute of Business Science

Bachelor of Science (BS) - Computer Science,